Inventory of the James Robert Huntley papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- E. Carlson correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 99: 1)
- H. Kissinger correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 99: 2)
- S. Butler correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 99: 3)
- R. Sneider correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 99: 4)
- J. Pritchard correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 99: 5)
- G. Franklin correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 99: 6)
- Consortium for Atlantic Pacific Affairs (CAPA)
  - Washington D.C., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 99: 7-8)
  - East Coast, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 99: 9)
  - New York City, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 99: 10)
  - Chicago and Midwest, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 99: 11)
  - California, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 99: 12)
  - Organization, plans, and meetings, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 99: 13-14)
- Council for A Community of Democracies (CCD)
  - Associate members, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 100: 1-3)
  - United Kingdom memoranda, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 100: 4)
  - Board correspondence and papers, 1997-2004 (Box-folder 100: 5)
  - Website, 2001 (Box-folder 100: 6)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 100: 7)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 100: 8)
  - Minutes and agendas, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 100: 9)
  - Programs and proposals, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 100: 10)
  - International, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 100: 11)
  - Bennington proposals and projects, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 101: 1)
  - 21st Century Foundation, Canada correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 101: 2)
  - 21st Century Foundation and CCD, Mactaggart correspondence, 1987-2001 (Box-folder 101: 3)
  - Fundraising, Microsoft Corporation, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 101: 4)
  - Jackson Foundation correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 101: 5-6)
  - Board, organization correspondence, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 101: 7-8)
  - Mission statement and purpose, correspondence, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 101: 9)
  - "Vision of CCD," exercise and paper, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 101: 10)
  - Institute of World Community Studies, 1985-2003 (Box-folder 102: 1)
  - Pacific Northwest Exploratory Group, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 102: 2-3)
- Institute for Global Democracy, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 102: 4)
- Institute for Global and Regional Security Studies, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 102: 5)
- Institute for Global and Regional Security Studies, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 102: 6)
- Democracy Coalition Project, 2001 (Box-folder 102: 7)
- Stimson Center, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 102: 8)
- International Democracy Parliamentarian Assembly, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 102: 9)
- Community of Democracies, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 102: 10)
- Higher education project, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 102: 11)
- Democracy Education Initiative, 2003 (Box-folder 102: 12)
- U.N. Democracies Caucus, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 102: 13)
- Council on Foreign Relations/Democracies Planning Group, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 102: 14)
- Democracy Center and Fund, 2004 (Box-folder 102: 15)
- IDEA, 2004 (Box-folder 102: 16)
- Energy initiative, 2004 (Box-folder 102: 17)
- U.S.-Middle East partnership, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 102: 18)
- September 11th reactions, 2001 (Box-folder 102: 19)
- Council for A Community of Democracies (CCD)
  - CCD and the U.S. government, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 103: 1)
  - World Forum on Democracy, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 103: 2)
  - Bush Administration, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 103: 3)
  - Seoul Community of Democracies meeting, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 103: 4)
  - Participants for Seoul Community of Democracies meeting, 2002 (Box-folder 103: 5)
  - Community of Democracies meetings and conferences, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 103: 6)
  - CCD and NGOs correspondence, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 103: 7)
  - Freedom House, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 103: 8)
  - CCD and NED, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 103: 9)
  - Memoranda and articles, 1993-2004 (Box-folder 103: 10-11)
  - Public relations and publicity, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 103: 12-13)
- Consortium for Atlantic-Pacific Affairs (CAPA)
  - Correspondence, William Olson, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 104: 1-2)
  - Administration, future staff, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 104: 3)
  - Program curriculum ideas, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 104: 4)
- The Economist Diary, 1966 (Box-folder 104: 5)
- The Economist Diary, 1970 (Box-folder 104: 6)
- The Economist Diary, 1961-1969 (Boxes 105-106)
- "Adressbuch der Deutsch-Amerikanischen Zusammenarbeit,", undated (Box 107)
- "Host Family Handbook,", 1982 (Box 107)
- "Passport: International Student Handbook,", 1984 (Box 107)
- Notebook, undated (Box 107)
- Germany, notebook, undated (Box 107)
- "Austausch über den Atlantik 1984," (Box 107)
- "Think Exchange!,", 1985 (Box 107)
- "International Education: The Unfinished Agenda,", 1983 (Box 107)
- "Bridging the Gap: Letters from German Youth Participating in the Congress-Bundestag Exchange Program,", 1985 (Box 107)
- "The Congress Bundestag Program: Parlamentarisches Patenschaftsprogramm,", 1985 (Box 107)
- "Bridging the Gap: Instructor's Manual (Lehrerbeiheft),", 1983 (Box 107)
- "Bridging the Gap: Or Getting to Know A Foreign Country in Twenty Easy Lessons" Heft 1 to 4, 1984-1985 (Box 107)
- "Achtung Aufnahme!,", 1985 (Box 107)
- "Bayerischer Jugendring,", undated (Box 107)
- The Economist Diary, 1959 (Box 107)
- "The Atlantic Papers 3: The Dollar Crisis and Europe,", 1971 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 1: Military Forces and Political Conflicts in the Mediterranean,", 1970 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 4: Europe and America at the Crossroads,", 1971 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 2: Europe and Nuclear Energy,", 1972 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 6: North-South, Developing a New Relationship,", 1975 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 1: Latin America in Transition,", 1971 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 4: A Future for European Agriculture,", 1970 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 2: Europe and Technology,", 1970 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 1: The Western World and Energy,", 1974 (Box 108)
- "The Atlantic Papers 4: The Decisive Years Ahead,", 1972 (Box 108)
- "Programm-Informationen Zum Parlamentarischen Patenschaftsprogramm,", undated (Box 108)
- "International Joint Commission- Rules of Procedure and Text of Treaty,", 1965 (Box 108)
- "The Educational System in the Federal Republic of Germany: Governance, Structures, Courses,", undated (Box 108)
- "The Triangle Papers 17: Energy- Managing the Transition,", 1978 (Box 108)
- "The Triangle Papers 15: An Overview of East-West Relations,", 1978 (Box 108)
- Non-governmental organizations (NGOs)
  - Committee for a World Parliament (COPAM), 2000 (Box-folder 109: 1)
  - Con-West, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 109: 2-3)
  - The Consortium, 1981 (Box-folder 109: 4)
  - The Citizen's Network, 1988 (Box-folder 109: 5)
  - Club of Madrid, 2003 (Box-folder 109: 6)
  - Club of Rome, 1979 (Box-folder 109: 7)
  - Coalition for Peace Through Security, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 109: 8)
  - College of the Atlantic, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 109: 9)
  - The College of William and Mary, Reves Center, 1992 (Box-folder 109: 10)
  - Comitato Atlantico, 1982 (Box-folder 109: 11)
  - Comité D'Action Pour les Etats-Unis D'Europe, 1967 (Box-folder 109: 12)
  - The Commission on Global Governance, 1995 (Box-folder 109: 13)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1989 (Box-folder 109: 14)
  - Consortium for Atlantic-Pacific Affairs (CAPA) correspondence, 1985 (Box-folder 109: 15)
  - Conference on the Atlantic Community (CONTAC), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 109: 16)
  - Con-West (Europe), 1982-1986 (Box-folder 109: 17)
  - Committee on Atlantic Studies, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 109: 18)
  - Committee for Economic Development of Australia, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 109: 19)
  - Committee for the Free World, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 109: 20)
  - Conference Group on German Politics, 1982 (Box-folder 109: 21)
  - Conference Permanente Europe-Etats-Unis, 1982 (Box-folder 109: 22)
  - Conference of World Regions, 1994 (Box-folder 109: 23)
  - Continuing Education in International Affairs, 1979 (Box-folder 109: 24)
  - Council for Advancement of Citizenship, 1985 (Box-folder 109: 25)
  - Council for the Decade of Democracy, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 109: 26)
  - Council for Education in World Citizenship, 1999 (Box-folder 109: 27)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1976-1992 (Box-folder 110: 1-2)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1979 (Box-folder 110: 3)
  - Center for the Study of Federalism, 1984 (Box-folder 110: 4)
  - Centre for the Study of International Institutions, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 110: 5)
  - Center of Pacific Affairs, 1981 (Box-folder 110: 6)
  - Center for party Development, undated (Box-folder 110: 7)
  - Centre d'Etudes Industrielles, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 110: 8)
  - Center for International Relations, 1982 (Box-folder 110: 9)
  - Cerdet, undated (Box-folder 110: 10)
  - Centre for International Studies, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 110: 11)
  - Center for West European Studies, 1995 (Box-folder 110: 12)
  - Center for Research and Documentation on the European Community, 1985 (Box-folder 110: 13)
  - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, 1972-1992 (Box-folder 110: 14-15)
  - China Relations Council, Washington State, 1979 (Box-folder 110: 16)
  - Comité des Intellectuels Pour L'Europe des Libertés (CIEL), 1978-1982 (Box-folder 110: 17)
  - Centre International de Formation Européenne (CIFE), 1982-2004 (Box-folder 110: 18)
  - Centre for European Policy Studies, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 111: 1)
  - Centre for Foreign Policy Studies, undated (Box-folder 111: 2)
  - Centre for Human Rights and Responsibilities, 1981 (Box-folder 111: 3)
  - Centre for Independent Studies, 1981 (Box-folder 111: 4)
  - Center for International Affairs, 1982 (Box-folder 111: 5)
  - Center for International Business, 1981 (Box-folder 111: 6)
  - UCLA Center for International and Strategic Affairs, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 111: 7)
  - Centre for Legislative Exchange, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 111: 8)
  - Lyman Lemnitzer Center for NATO Studies, 1982 (Box-folder 111: 9)
  - Annenberg Center for Study of American Experiences, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 111: 10)
  - NGOs in Eastern Europe, 1990 (Box-folder 111: 11)
  - East-West Center, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 111: 12-13)
  - Atlantic Visitors Association, 1982 (Box-folder 112: 1)
  - Australian Association for Cultural Freedom, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 112: 2)
  - The Banff Centre, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 112: 3)
  - Bergedorf Round Table, 1981 (Box-folder 112: 4)
  - Business and Industry Advisory Committee (BIAC), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 112: 5)
  - American Friends of Bilderberg, 1966, 1982 (Box-folder 112: 6)
  - Bretton Woods Committee, 1986 (Box-folder 112: 7)
  - Atlantic Council of the UK, 1979-1998 (Box-folder 112: 8)
  - British Atlantic Committee, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 112: 9)
  - British Atlantic Group of Young Politicians, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 112: 10)
  - British Fulbright Scholars Association, 1982 (Box-folder 112: 11)
  - Brookings Institution, 1978 (Box-folder 112: 12)
  - Business Council of International Understanding (BCIU), 1975-1983 (Box-folder 112: 13)
  - Canadian-American Committee, 1976 (Box-folder 112: 14)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 112: 15)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1979 (Box-folder 112: 16)
  - Center for American Studies, 1981 (Box-folder 112: 17)
  - Center for Applied studies in International Negotiations, 1982 (Box-folder 112: 18)
  - Center for Civil Society, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 112: 19)
  - The Center for Democracy, 1985 (Box-folder 112: 20)
  - The Atlantic Institute for International Affairs, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 113: 1)
  - The Atlantic Institute for International Affairs, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 113: 2)
  - The Atlantic Institute for International Affairs, 1982-2002 (Box-folder 113: 3)
  - Atlantic Treaty Association, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 113: 4)
  - Atlantic Treaty Association, 1982-2001 (Box-folder 113: 5)
- "The Threats to Freedom: the Atlantic Response,", 1977 (Box-folder 113: 6)
- "The Battle for Allied Solidarity in an Interdependent World,", 1976 (Box-folder 113: 7)
- "Thirty Years of Partnership for Peace,", 1979 (Box-folder 113: 8)
- "The Security of North Sea Oil and the Over-all Soviet Naval Threat,", 1975 (Box-folder 113: 9)
- "M.B.F.R. (Mutual and Balanced Force Reductions) Its Origins and Perspectives,", 1974 (Box-folder 113: 10)
- "Impediments to the Free Flow of Information Between East and West,", 1973 (Box-folder 113: 11)
- "The Japan Foundation,", 1974 (Box-folder 113: 12)
- "Soviet Foreign Policy: Its Many Facets and Its Real Objectives,", 1975 (Box-folder 113: 13)
- "Atlantic Treaty Association 28th Annual Assembly Programme", 1982 (Box-folder 113: 14)
- "Atlantic Treaty Association 27th Annual Assembly Programme,", 1981 (Box-folder 113: 15)
- Attachments to Letter to Lt. Gen. B. Scowcroft, "International Community Building,", 1981 (Box 114)
- "Private Initiatives and the Cohesion of the Western Democracies; Part III: Directory of Organizations,", 1983 (Box 114)
- "The Atlantic Papers: Protectionism or Industrial Adjustment?,", 1980 (Box 114)
- "The Atlantic Papers: Economic Adjustment to an Energy-Short World,", 1980 (Box 114)
- "The Atlantic Papers: Uranium, Nonproliferation and Energy Security,", 1980 (Box 114)
- "The Atlantic Papers: Changing Structures in the World Oil Market,", 1981 (Box 114)
- "The Atlantic Papers: Japan and the Pacific Basin,", 1980 (Box 114)
- The Economist Diary, 1960 (Box 114)
- NGO directory, 1982 (Box-folder 115: 1-2)
- NGO survey plans, 1981 (Box-folder 115: 3-4)
- "Private Initiatives and the Cohesion of the Western Democracies,", 1983 (Box-folder 115: 5)
- "Private Initiatives, Public Good and Cohesion of the West,", 1983 (Box-folder 116: 1)
- Correspondence concerning "Uniting the Democracies,", 1980-1981 (Box-folder 116: 2)
- Washington Convention Center, 1988 (Box-folder 116: 3-4)
- Life of Andrew Carnegie, 1989 (Box-folder 116: 5)
- Andrew Carnegie materials, 1989 (Box-folder 116: 6)
- NGO survey, collated questionnaires, 1983 (Box-folder 117: 1-2)
- "Correspondents World Wide,", 1974 (Box-folder 117: 3-5)
- Battelle benefits program, 1994 (Box-folder 117: 6)
- Association to Unite the Democracies (AUD), Next Century Initiative (NCI)
  - Finance, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 118: 1-3)
  - Proposals, 1992 (Box-folder 118: 4)
  - Planning and organization, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 118: 5-6)
  - G-7 Symposium, 1994 (Box-folder 118: 7)
  - Symposium on Governance, 1993 (Box-folder 118: 8)
  - "General Social and Economic Analysis of Britain Today" (written for Battelle Institute), 1972 (Box-folder 118: 9)
  - Work with other NGOs, 1993 (Box-folder 119: 1)
  - Congress and administration, 1993 (Box-folder 119: 2)
  - White House operations, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 119: 3)
  - G-7 report, 1994 (Box-folder 119: 4-5)
  - Conference, finance, 1993 (Box-folder 119: 6-7)
  - Principals' meeting, 1993 (Box-folder 119: 8-9)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 120: 1)
  - "Towards A Better World Order" prospectus, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 120: 2)
  - Committee structure and composition for NCI, 1992 (Box-folder 120: 3)
  - Action Committee, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 120: 4)
  - Sponsors Committee, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 120: 5-6)
  - Steering Group, 1993 (Box-folder 120: 7-8)
  - Work plan, 1993 (Box-folder 120: 9)
  - John Whitehead correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 121: 1)
  - Bill Brock correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 121: 2)
  - NCI Prospectus, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 121: 3)
  - Correspondence, Richardson, Raymond, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 121: 4-6)
  - Action plan and mission statements, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 121: 7)
  - Correspondence, Kane, Phibbs, Payne, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 121: 8)
  - Senator Brock visit, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 121: 9)
  - Seattle architecture members, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 121: 10)
  - 1957 Bruges Conference, 2002 (Box-folder 122: 1)
  - "Political Community and the North Atlantic Area,", 1957 (Box-folder 122: 2)
  - "The Challenge of Building an International Community,", 1981 (Box-folder 122: 3)
  - Seattle materials and articles, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 122: 4)
  - Microsoft correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 122: 5)
  - Weyerhaeuser Company, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 122: 6)
  - Center for International Governance, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 122: 7)
  - Funding contributions, 1992 (Box-folder 122: 8)
  - Craig Smith correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 122: 9)
  - Boeing correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 122: 10)
  - Haub correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 122: 11)
  - Booth Gardner correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 122: 12)
  - Jackson correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 122: 13)
  - Documents, reports, and proposals, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 122: 14)
- Draft Letters to Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS) directors, 1984 (Box-folder 123: 1)
- Project Democracy, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 123: 2)
- Shultz speech, "Unity and Dissent,", 1986 (Box-folder 123: 3)
- Cooper article, "Monetary System,", 1984 (Box-folder 123: 4)
- 1984 (Box-folder 123: 5)
- Democracy articles, 1982 (Box-folder 123: 6)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS) negotiations and settlement, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 123: 7)
- Orbis article, "The Role of Leadership,", 1966 (Box-folder 123: 8)
- Japanese-Western relations, 1976 (Box-folder 123: 9)
- "Historic Origins of the Modern Atlantic System,", 1976 (Box-folder 123: 10)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS)
  - Resignation
    - Letters of support, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 124: 1)
    - A. Barnett correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 124: 2)
    - December 5th board meeting, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 3)
    - Evidence, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 124: 4-5)
    - Executive Committee, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 6)
    - Theodore C. Achilles correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 7)
    - "Goodbye letters,", 1984 (Box-folder 124: 8)
    - Executive Committee exhibits, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 9)
    - Executive Committee reports, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 10)
  - 1985 activities, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 125: 1)
  - Conference and reports, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 2)
  - American foundations, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 125: 3)
  - Resignation statement to Executive Committee, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 4)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 125: 5)
  - President's letter, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 6)
  - "The Interrelationship of Atlantic and Pacific Issues," project, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 7)
  - Montebello lease, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 125: 8)
  - Resignation notes, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 9)
  - Board meeting documents, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 10)
  - Standing Conference of Atlantic Organizations, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 126: 1-2)
- "1984 and Beyond: A Reaffirmation of Values," (Box-folder 126: 3)
- "North Atlantic Assembly Report of the Sub-Committee on the Successor Generation,", 1982 (Box-folder 126: 4)
- "Directory of Atlantic Organisations,", 1977 (Box-folder 126: 5)
- "Atlantic Treaty Association Programme- NATO: New Opportunities,", 1984 (Box-folder 126: 6)
- The World and the School, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 126: 7-9)
- Private Voluntary Associations (PVA) survey collated questionnaires, 1983 (Box-folder 126: 10-12)
- Atlantic Colleges materials, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 127: 1)
- Europe and America reviews, comments, letters scrapbook, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 127: 2)
- "Managing Across Cultures,", 1974 (Box-folder 127: 3)
- Private Voluntary Associations (PVA) notes and materials, 1983 (Box-folder 127: 4)
- Directory of Atlantic Organizations, 1974 (Box-folder 127: 5)
- Rohatyn correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 128: 1)
- Trip itineraries and reservations, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 128: 2-3)
- Europe trip itineraries and correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 128: 4)
- Wilton Park trip itinerary and materials, 1989 (Box-folder 128: 5)
- Business trips, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 128: 6-7)
- Aborted Europe trips, 1990 (Box-folder 128: 8-9)
- Investors Overseas Service (IOS) and IOS Foundation, 1970 (Box-folder 128: 10)
- German Marshall Fund of the United States, 1972 (Box-folder 128: 11)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 128: 12)
- Ford Foundation, 1973-2003 (Box-folder 128: 13)
- Foundation for the Cohesion of the West, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 129: 1)
- All-Democracies Conference, 1988 (Box-folder 129: 2)
- A. Hoffman correspondence, 1988-2001 (Box-folder 129: 3-5)
- Ford Foundation reports, 1949-1965 (Box-folder 129: 6)
- Ford Foundation Letters, newsletter, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 129: 7)
- Ford Foundation materials, 1950-2003 (Box-folder 129: 8)
- Vancouver trip, 1996 (Box-folder 129: 9)
- Pacific Basin expansion, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 130: 1)
- Independent sector, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 130: 2)
- Basic country groupings chart, 1996 (Box-folder 130: 3)
- Democratic solidarity pamphlet, 1985 (Box-folder 130: 4)
- Committees for a Community of Democracies proposal, "Architecture for the New World Order,", 1991 (Box-folder 130: 5)
- "Marshall Plan of Modern Ideas" article, 1991 (Box-folder 130: 6)
- Layne article and responses, 1994 (Box-folder 130: 7)
- "Seattle Can Be Hub" article, 1994 (Box-folder 130: 8)
- Northwest Colloquium on International Security, 1995 (Box-folder 130: 9)
- Expansion of NATO articles, 1997 (Box-folder 130: 10)
- Pax Democratica
  - Various Chapters, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 130: 11)
  - Chapter 1, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 1)
  - Chapter 2, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 2)
  - Chapter 3, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 3)
  - Chapter 4, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 4)
  - Chapter 5, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 5)
  - Chapter 6, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 6)
  - Chapter 7, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 131: 7)
  - Early ideas and concepts, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 131: 8)
- International Standing Conference on Philanthropy (INTERPHIL) Foundations, 1970-1989 (Box-folder 131: 9-10)
- "Governance of the Whole,", 1991-1996 (Box-folder 132: 1)
- Economy articles, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 132: 2)
- Security articles, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 132: 3)
- Human rights articles, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 132: 4)
- Environment articles and correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 132: 5)
- Science and technology articles and correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 132: 6)
- Pax Democratica
  - Synopsis, 1995 (Box-folder 132: 7)
  - Source material, 1995 (Box-folder 132: 8)
  - Chapter 8, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 132: 9)
  - Chapter 9 and appendix materials, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 132: 10-12)
  - Draft materials, 1996 (Box-folder 132: 13)
- The New Criterion, Vol. 1 to 4, 1983-1986 (Box 133)
- SSA Time Organizer, 1981-1988 (Boxes 134-135)
- Interplay of European/American Affairs, 1968 (Box 136)
- Interplay- The Magazine of International Affairs, Vol. 3, 1969-1970 (Box 136)
- The New Criterion, Vol. 2 to 3, 1984-1985 (Box 136)
- Congress-Bundestag Rotary Exchange Program evaluation, 1985 (Box 137)
- Two card file boxes, 1968 (Box 137)
- Interplay of European/American Affairs, Vol. 1, No. 1 to 8, 1967-1968 (Box 137)
- Interplay- The Magazine of International Affairs, Vol. 2 to 3, 1968-1969 (Box 137)
- SSA Time Organizer, 1989-1990 (Box 138)
- Battelle Memorial Institute, Science and Human Affairs Program, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 139: 1-2)
- Association to Unite the Democracies
  - Arlie meetings and working groups, 1992 (Box-folder 139: 3)
  - Arlie meeting substance and agenda, 1992 (Box-folder 139: 4-6)
- 21st century policy issues, 2000 (Box-folder 139: 7)
- Battelle Memorial Institute
  - "Key Technologies: The 1980s,", 1981 (Box-folder 140: 1)
  - "World Energy in the 1980s," (Box-folder 140: 2)
  - "World Trade in the 1980s," (Box-folder 140: 3)
- Wilton Park Journal, No. 41 to 65, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 140: 4)
- Seminar notebook, "World Business and World Politics,", 1982 (Box-folder 141: 1)
- World Politics Monitor, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 141: 2)
- "World Politics in the 1980s: First Annual Review,", 1981 (Box-folder 141: 3)
- "World Politics in the 1980s: Second Annual Review,", 1982 (Box-folder 141: 4)
- "Battelle: The U.S. Social, Political, and Economic Environment for the 1980s,", 1981 (Box-folder 141: 5)
- Public opinion reports and summaries, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 142: 1)